《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
这位是雷吉纳德・佩恩
This is, Reginald Payne.
我们是老战友  少爷
We served together, sir.
请安心在这里待几天吧
Please, feel free to stay with us a few days.
你在偷我们的东西
You're stealing from us?
阿诺德・弗拉斯
Arnold Flass.
你因杀害利昂・温克勒被捕了
You're under arrest for the murder of Leon Winkler.
内务处说他是自杀
I.A. ruled it a suicide.
阿诺德・弗拉斯  你被捕了
Arnold Flass, you're under arrest.
我有人罩着
I'm protected.
那么  惹事的就是你吗
So... you're the one causing all of the fuss.
你休想从我身上拿走任何东西
You will take nothing from me.
是吗
Really?
不
No!
他没什么切实证据
He has nothing concrete.
现在是对那孩子采取行动的最佳时机
Now's the time to make a move on the kid.
食堂选择不多
Slim pickings at the food court.
-给你买了百吉饼  -谢谢
- Brought you a bagel. - Thanks.
没给伤患买吗
Nothing for the invalid?
抱歉  只能吃医院的食物
Sorry. Hospital food only.
-医生嘱咐  感觉怎样  -还好
- Doctor's orders. How you feeling? - All right.
被刺伤了点
Had a slight... puncture.
有点漏
Leaked a bit.
昨晚的事你估计都记不清了
So I know last night must be kind of a blur,
但你知道是谁干的吗
but do you have any idea who did this?
是...
It-it was...
当时很黑  非常黑
It was dark. It was very dark.
看到了
Saw a...
一道黑影  然后...
shadow and...
我的恩人布鲁斯少爷就站在我身边了
my savior Master Bruce was leaning over me.
你看到那人的长相了吗
Did you get a look at the guy?
没有
No.
抱歉  警监不停打电话
Sorry. My captain keeps calling.
没事的  警探
It's fine, Detective.
-去吧  -没事  我可以留下
- Just-just go. - No, I can stay.
我真的很感谢你陪着布鲁斯少爷
I really appreciate you sitting with Master Bruce,
但如你所见  我都没事了
but as you can see, I'm completely fine.
走吧
Go.
好  我尽量待会儿来看你们
All right. I'll try and stop by later.
再次谢谢你能来  警探
Thank you again for coming, Detective.
为什么不告诉他实情
Why not tell him the truth?
信不信由你  布鲁斯少爷  雷吉是我朋友
Well, believe it or not, Master Bruce, Reggie's a mate,
你不能让警察去抓朋友啊
and you don't set coppers on your mates, do you?
但他差点杀了你
But he nearly killed you.
我跟那混球一起当过兵
I served with that bastard.
要有人去找他  也得是我
Anyone sorts him out, it's me-- nobody else.
否则不义气
It wouldn't be right.
他为什么要捅你
Why would he stab you?
这是个好问题
That's a bloody good question.
还是个
And one...
我想弄明白的问题
I mean to find out.
那疯子一天不抓回来
'Cause longer that bloody lunatic's out on the loose...
想找到他就越难
...the harder it's gonna be to find him.
你去...
Now, you just...
回床上去  阿尔弗雷德
G-get back in bed, Alfred.
把袍子给我
Just pass me my robe.
回床上去
Get back in bed!
这是命令
That's an order.
你醒了
You're awake.
好极了
Wonderful.
我这是...
How long have I been...
睡了多久吗
Asleep?
就从昨晚到现在
Just since last night.
感觉如何
How do you feel?
头疼欲裂
My head hurts.
预料之中
To be expected.
让我看看
May I?
你是谁
Who are you?
弗兰西斯・杜马赫医生
Dr. Francis Dulmacher.
这里的创建者
Founder of this facility.
很荣幸
A pleasure.
我为见你可是费尽心思啊  医生
I've gone to great lengths to meet you, Doctor.
的确如此
Indeed you have.
我得说  你们的体质令人赞叹
I must say you have a remarkable constitution.
真希望我所有病人都这样
I wish I could say the same of all my patients.
我现在是病人了吗
So I'm a patient now?
不再是囚犯了吗
No longer a prisoner?
我说实话  我不知道你该算什么
I confess I don't know what you are.
你控制了地下室
You seize control of the basement,
绑架了我的一名守卫
take one of my guards hostage,
然后把自己的眼睛挖出来了
then scoop out your own eye.
我该拿你怎么办
What am I to do with you?
很简单  让我当你的左右手
Simple. Make me your right hand.
很高兴你还会开玩笑
I'm glad to see you've retained your sense of humor.
我没开玩笑
I'm not joking.
过去十年里
For the past ten years,
我一直都是卡麦・法尔科内的得力手下
I've been Carmine Falcone's top lieutenant.
不好意思  没听过那个名字
I'm afraid the name means nothing to me.
我被关进了地下牢房  又饿又孤独
I woke up hungry and alone in an underground cell.
不到一周  我就把这里闹得天翻地覆
In less than a week, I brought this place to a standstill.
你试过了与我为敌
Now, you've had me as your enemy.
你难道不希望我跟你站一边吗
Wouldn't you rather have me as your friend?
真有活力
Such vim.
真有派头
Such... panache.
好极了
Bravo.
现在你该吃饭了
And now you should eat.
我让护士送点食物进来
I'll have a nurse come in with some food.
咱们等会儿再聊
We'll talk more later.
眼睛这东西挺难搞的
Tricky things, eyes.
目前我们的存货少得可怜
Our stock is frightfully low at the moment.
很抱歉了
Oh, and apologies.
我们没找到与你原来颜色相同的
We couldn't match your original color.
咱们等下再聊
We'll talk soon.
本剧集字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译制作
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再整理而成
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
翻译：艾瑞卡   DustD   木浅薰   Silence   charcie   灰灰是菇凉
翻译：爵士年代蓬蓬裙   草草              特效：宝宝
时间轴：凭陵新月   兜兜兜爹   Kallen   最可爱的小胖子
后期：饿得慌               校对&总监：草草
哥谭
第一季  第十八集
缉毒组警探无罪释放  谋杀罪名撤销
这不可能
This can't be true.
我正在给地检官准备案子
I was prepping the case for the D.A.
结果今天早上就听到了消息
when word came down this morning.
显然媒体昨晚就知道了
Press got it last night, of course.
我们手上有谋杀凶器
We had the murder weapon.
上边有弗拉斯的指纹
With Flass's prints.
这不可能
There's no way.
显然  辩方找来了一位证人
Apparently, the defense dug up a witness,
洗清了弗拉斯的罪名
cleared Flass of all charges.
-什么证人  -不知道
- What witness? - No idea.
只有法官和首席律师知道
Only the judge and the lead attorneys were privy,
而我们可敬的地检官不肯说
and our honorable D.A. is staying mum.
那传唤呢
What about a subpoena?
我们没有足够的理由
We don't have sufficient grounds.
但是我四处打听了一下
But I did a little snooping around.
怎么样
And?
那位神秘证人是洛布局长提供的
The mystery witness was provided by Commissioner Loeb.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
洛布恢复了弗拉斯缉毒组组长的身份
Loeb's reinstating Flass as head of Narco.
更糟
Worse.
他宣布支持弗拉斯参加
He announced he's backing Flass for president
即将到来的警察工会主席的竞选
of the policemen's union in the upcoming election.
所以你是说一个我们已知是毒贩子
So you're telling me a man we know is a drug dealer
和杀人凶手的人
and a murderer
将有可能在哥谭市警局出任要职
is gonna potentially hold a major position in the GCPD?
洛布显然是在示威
Clearly, Loeb's sending a message.
这不可容忍
This is not gonna stand.
我和你一样失望  吉姆
Look, I'm just as upset about this as you are, Jim,
但他是局长
but it's the commissioner.
所以情况更糟了
Which is what makes it worse.
吉姆  吉姆
Jim! Jim!
吉姆
Jimbo.
你听到好消息了吗
You heard the good news?
伙计们正准备在奥唐丽餐厅给我开场回归宴
Hey, the boys are throwing me a welcome back down at O'Donnelys.
不知道你想不想来看看
Figure you want to stop by.
支持一下你的准新主席
Show support for your soon-to-be new president.
我看你还是别急着庆祝
I wouldn't celebrate just yet.
你就是学不乖
You just don't learn.
还想搞掉我呢
Still want to take me down.
我就像是凤凰
I'm like the phoenix.
我会浴火重生
I'll just rise
一次  一次  又一次
again and again and again.
戈登警探
Ah, Detective Gordon.
我就预感你会来找我
I had a presentiment I might be seeing you.
阿诺德・弗拉斯是个杀人犯
Arnold Flass is a murderer.
他应该待在监狱里
He belongs in jail.
弗拉斯警探依法无罪释放
Detective Flass was legally exonerated.
法官听取了证词  案件结束了
The judge heard testimony. The case is closed.
你是动用关系安排他获释
You used your connections to orchestrate his release.
你玷污了体制
You perverted the system.
暴躁和天真是个坏组合
Petulance and naiveté are a bad combination.
输了就要认命
Know when you're beaten.
弗拉斯的调查我介入很深
I was knee-deep in the Flass investigation.
没有人能有足够的可信度
There is no one with enough credibility
来推翻我们的证据
to trump our evidence.
我很喜欢不可动摇的信念
I do enjoy when unwavering certainty
被真相击碎的时刻
is undermined by the truth.
看着镜头  说出你的名字
Look into the camera, state your name
还有为什么会在这里
and why you're here.
我是哈维・布洛克警探
My name is Detective Harvey Bullock,
我使用了假证据指证了
and I presented false evidence against
我哥谭市警局同事  阿诺德・弗拉斯警探
my fellow GCPD detective, Arnold Flass.
你在这儿啊
Hey, there you are.
老兄  我感觉就像是昨晚有一群牛
Aw, dude. Feel like a herd of cattle had a dance party
在脑子里开了一场舞会
in my head last night.
有什么事吗
What's up?
你为什么要撒谎保弗拉斯
Why the hell would you lie to exonerate Flass?
别否认  我都看到录像带了
Don't deny it. I saw the tape.
我也没打算否认
I'm not denying anything.
我那是迫不得已
I did what I had to do.
如果我不按洛布说的做  早就被开除了
If I didn't do what Loeb told me to do, I would've lost my job.
说不定都进监狱了
Probably gone to prison.
他有你什么把柄
What does he have on you?
哈维
Harvey.
你真以为你是唯一一个
Do you honestly think you're the only one
被人命令带一个混混去码头
who had the orders to take a punk down to the end of a pier
一枪崩了他的人吗
and put a bullet in his head? Huh?
区别在于我那个科波特没回来
The difference is my Cobblepot didn't come back.
你杀的是谁
Who'd you kill?
就一个黑帮小混混
Some scumbag mobster.
有天看到他从夜店出来
Caught him coming out of a club one night.
带我的警司给了我把枪然后拿枪指着我
My sergeant put a gun in my hand, held another to my head,
说  你自己选
and said, "Make a choice."
我选择了活
I decided to keep breathing.
该死  哈维
Damn it, Harvey.
怎么了
So what?
你要怎么办  抓我吗  那你抓吧
What are you gonna do? Arrest me? Go ahead. Arrest me.
别收手啊
But don't stop there.
哥谭市警局半数警察都有个科波特
Half the cops in the GCPD have a Cobblepot,
洛布有他们所有人的把柄
and Loeb has the goods on all of them.
这就是洛布的专长
That is what Loeb does.
那到此为止了
Well, it ends now.
吉姆
Jim, hey.
查弗拉斯已经够糟了
Going after Flass was bad enough.
你要查洛布那就是自杀  没其他可能
Going after Loeb is suicide, plain and simple.
怎么
So what?
我就该保持沉默
Am I supposed to stay quiet?
像你们其他人那样乖乖听话
Fall in line like the rest of you?
这是个好主意
That would be a good idea.
我要这么做还不如直接辞职
Day I do that is the day I quit being a cop.
天哪
Oh, my.
有趣的事实
Fun fact.
人类通过信息素来吸引异性
The human species attracts members of the opposite sex via pheromones
而信息素由唾液  汗液和尿液分泌
secreted through saliva, sweat and urine.
好恶心
Gross.
但是
But...
用这种兽性的方式选择合适伴侣
one can't always trust such an animalistic method
并不总是可靠的
to find a suitable partner.
你到底想说什么
What are you trying to tell me?
阿诺德・弗拉斯被释放了
Arnold Flass was released.
我知道你们俩本来在交往
I know that you two were dating,
如果你们之间的好感不是出于理智
and if the attraction wasn't intellectual--
否则也不会选那个蛮人了
how could it be with that gorilla?--
那吸引肯定是来自肉欲
then it must be physical.
他是个很坏很坏的...
He's just... he's such a bad, bad, bad...
谢谢你的关心
I appreciate your concern.
但你想多了
But it won't be necessary.
我现在知道世界上还有比
I've realized there are far better men
阿诺德・弗拉斯好的多的人
in the world than Arnold Flass.
你是说洛布这些年一直在搜集警察的把柄
So Loeb's been collecting dirt on cops for years
还用它来控制警局
and using it to control the department.
恐怕不只如此
I doubt it stops there.
可能还涉及商界和政界
He's probably got leverage on businessmen, politicians.
他可没有我的把柄
He's got nothing on me.
只是确认一下
Just checking.
不管怎样  这就是他有影响力的原因
Anyway, yeah, that's the source of all his power.
而你打算虎口夺食
And you want to steal the dragon's gold.
如果能找到他搜集的证据并毁掉
If we find his cache of evidence and destroy it,
那他就是没牙的老虎了
he'll be toothless.
我了解洛布
Oh, I know Loeb.
他肯定藏的很好
He won't keep it anywhere obvious.
我们可以监视他  让他自己暴露
We could watch him, hope he leads us to it.
没那么多时间了
We don't have that kind of time.
洛布就没有什么曾经信任的人吗
Isn't there someone Loeb might have trusted?
闹翻的朋友
Ex-friends?
失和的妻子
An estranged wife?
他倒是结过婚
Well, he was married.
妻子20年前就死了
She died 20 years ago.
从楼梯上摔下来的
Fell down the stairs.
当时还有传言说是洛布杀的
Well, there were rumors Loeb killed her,
但也不了了之了
but nothing ever happened with it.
我还是不敢相信你搭档这么做了
Still can't believe about your partner.
他为什么这么做  洛布有他什么把柄
Why'd he do it? What's Loeb have on him?
我不知道
I don't know.
肯定很难受吧
Well, it's got to be rough.
我理解警察和搭档之间的关系
I know how it is with cops and their partners.
怎么了
What is it?
有什么事啊  丹特
What's the matter, Dent?
兰布斯塔的案子不是完结了吗
I thought that Lambusta case was settled.
而且我们为什么要在这儿见
And why the hell are we meeting here?
等会儿你就知道了
You'll see.
你认识吉姆・戈登吧
You know Jim Gordon?
到底是怎么回事
What the hell's going on?
坐下说吧
Have a seat.
洛布当上局长之前
Back before Loeb was Commissioner,
还是职位卑微的凶案组警察时  你俩曾是搭档
when he was a lowly homicide dick, you were his partner.
那是20年前的事了
Yeah? That was 20 years ago.
可我听说  警察间的搭档关系就像婚姻
But I always hear that cop partnerships are like marriages.
你们对彼此的了解胜于你们的妻子
You know each other better than your wives.
我说的对吗  吉姆
Isn't that right, Jim?
没错
That's right.
你在查洛布杀妻那个老掉牙的说法吗
You digging up that old story about Loeb killing his wife?
她死的时候  他和我在一起
He was with me when she died.
我们已经知道秘密档案的事了
We know about the secret files.
什么秘密档案
What secret files?
演得太棒了
Oh, that was good.
我几乎相信了他
I almost believed him.
-你呢  吉姆  -我不相信
- What about you, Jim? - No.
你们是不自量力  孩子  你们俩都是
You're out of your depth, kid. Both of you.
回头是岸吧
Swim back to shore.
他手上也有你的把柄  是吗
He's got something on you, too, doesn't he?
他逼你做了件事
He got you to do something for him.
是什么
What was it?
抢劫  威逼
Robbery? Coercion?
还是杀人
Murder?
一直以来  你因此而受制于他
And all this time, he's been using it to keep you under his thumb.
现在是你重获自由的机会
This is your chance to breathe easy again.
把握机会  格里格斯
Take it, Griggs.
我不知道你们俩在说什么
I don't know what you two are talking about.
如果我知道  我会叫你们去找陆西吧
If I did, I'd say talk to Xi Lu.
休伦街的华人簿记员
Chinese bookkeeper on Huron Street.
洛布总说  如果想安全存放一样东西
Loeb always said you want to keep something safe,
就把东西交给陆西
you give it to Xi Lu.
要带上布洛克吗
You want to bring in Bullock?
我们可能需要他
We might need him.
不用了
No.
谢谢你  乔
Thanks, Joe.
我说真的
I mean it.
我喜欢蓝色
I like the blue.
很高兴你喜欢
I'm so pleased.
病人开心  医生也开心
Happy patient, happy doctor.
哈里斯夫人
Mrs. Harris.
你好啊  医生
Hello, Doctor.
别忘了  6点在阳台听爵士乐
Don't forget-- jazz at 6:00 on the veranda,
但绷带拆除前别喝酒  好吗
but no martinis until the bandages come off, yes?
真乖
Good girl.
肾移植
Kidney transplant.
顺便免费给她整了容  她正需要呢
We threw in a new face for free, and none too soon.
但你需要稳定的器官供给
But you need a steady supply of organs.
是的
Yes.
因为你  这如今突然成了麻烦
Which is suddenly something of a problem, thanks to you.
但我也能帮你解决这个麻烦
But I'm also a solution.
地下室的人信任我
The people in the basement trust me.
让我管事
Put me in charge,
我向你保证  我能提供可靠的健康产品
and I promise you a dependable flow of healthy product.
或者我可以直接省去麻烦
Or I could save myself the trouble
把你和楼下的人都杀掉
and kill you and everyone downstairs.
如果你有那个选择  你早就会做了
Now, if that were an option, you would have done it already,
而且更不会把这么美丽的眼睛
and you surely wouldn't have wasted this beautiful eye
浪费在我身上
on little old me.
我想给你看点东西
I'd like to show you something.
人们把自己看做是独立独特的系统
People view themselves as unique, self-contained systems,
但我们只不过是一堆零件罢了
but we are merely a collection of parts.
如果我替换了你的眼睛  脸蛋和心脏时
What happens when I replace your eyes,
会怎么样呢
your face, your heart?
你什么时候会不再是你  而成为新的东西呢
When do you stop being you and become something new?
这令我很着迷
That's what fascinates me.
真有意思
Nice talk.
成交吗
Do we have a deal?
有条件
Conditionally.
我会让你回地下室
I will send you back to the basement,
你得把我的守卫弄回来  并向我证明
you will retrieve my guard, and then prove to me
你有能力向我提供人体
that you can provide me with the bodies.
考验我
A test.
要是我失败了呢
And if I fail?
失败者一样有用
Oh, those who fail me still have their uses.
你还记得前任办公室经理吧
You may remember my former office manager.
有趣吧
Amusing, no?
"然后我看着星星
"And then I looked at the stars,
查尔斯・狄更斯《远大前程》
想到一个人濒临冻死之际
and considered how awful it would be for a man
向那璀璨的繁星看去
to turn his face up to them as he froze to death,
却看不到援助或怜惜  那是多么糟糕"
and see no help or pity in the glittering multitude..."
"你..."
"You're..."
真愉快轻松啊
That's cheerful.
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
艾薇每周溜进医院几次
Ivy sneaks in a few times a week.
偷病人的东西吃
Steals food from the sickies.
她看到了你
She spotted you.
他还好吧
He okay?
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
谢谢
Thanks.
阿尔弗雷德被人捅了
Alfred was stabbed.
是他的老战友
It was a friend of his from the army.
真不幸
That sucks.
我觉得这都是因为我
I think he was there because of me.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我召集韦恩集团董事会开过会
I had a meeting with the board of Wayne Enterprises
跟他们说我在调查他们
to tell them I was investigating them,
于是他们就找了个我们会信任的人监视我们
so they sent someone we'd trust to spy on us.
他想找什么
What was he looking for?
我的几份文件不见了
Some of my files were missing.
我觉得他偷别的只是为了掩饰
I think the other things he stole were just cover.
如果我找到他  就可以查出谁雇的他
If I find him, I could find out who hired him.
他是一切的关键
He's-he's the key to everything.
你要去找他
You're gonna track him down?
不是吧  就凭你
Really? You?
我必须这么做
I-I have to.
这都是我害的
This... this is my fault.
小子  你疯了吧
Kid, you're out of your mind.
你看看他  你也想搞成这样吗
Look at him. Is that how you want to end up?
我不指望你能理解
I don't expect you to understand.
-我帮你  -不用
- I'll help. - No.
我不能再让别人因为我受伤了
I can't risk anybody else getting hurt on account of me.
你知道去哪找我
You know how to find me.
陆西
Xi Lu?
哥谭市警局  我是戈登警探
Detective Gordon, GCPD.
我们有几个问题想问你
We have a few questions we'd like to ask you.
我们能私下谈谈吗
Is there somewhere we can talk in private?
问吧  警探
Ask your questions, Detective.
是关于洛布局长的
It's about Commissioner Loeb.
你和他有业务往来  对吗
We understand you two have a business relationship?
我不认识洛布局长
I do not know Commissioner Loeb.
听着  老头
Listen, old man,
我们可以在十分钟内叫来一群助理地检官和警察
we can have a dozen ADAs and cops here in ten minutes.
你这儿每一块钱就都会被充公
They'll confiscate every dollar in this place,
你也得去坐牢
and you will go to jail.
你叫戈登
Your name is Gordon.
没错
That's right.
你是丹特
And you are Dent.
对
Yes.
等一下
Wait here.
好吧  不妙
Okay. Not good.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
放下武器
Drop your weapons now!
-戈登  -快跑
- Gordon...  - Yeah. Run!
快上来
Get in!
咱们得回去  你得请求支援
We got to go back there. You've got to call backup.
算了吧  五分钟后那儿就会被清干净
Forget it! The place will be cleaned out in five minutes.
多谢你来找我们
Thanks for stopping by.
我还有良心
I got enough on my conscience.
这是格里格斯的圈套
Griggs set us up.
现在洛布知道咱们在找他藏的证据
Now Loeb knows we're after his evidence cache.
格里格斯叫你们去的
Griggs sent you?
他为了保命不惜出卖任何人
Guy would turn on anyone to save his own skin.
你得狠狠吓他
You just got to scare him enough.
-我们试过了  -让我来
- We tried. - Let me.
相信我  律师  你这次还是别参与了
Counselor, trust me, you're gonna want to sit this one out.
给我个名字
I want a name!
-法尔科内  -什么
- Falcone! - What?!
他是唯一一个知道洛布藏东西地点的人
The only person who knows where Loeb keeps his stash!
是法尔科内
Falcone!
他们俩是一伙儿的
The two of them are in it together!
洛布和法尔科内
Loeb and Falcone!
你俩死定了
You two are dead men!
你们敢和洛布和法尔科内作对  你们完蛋了
You're going against Loeb and Falcone? You're dead!
快滚  趁我还没发火
Go! Before I lose my good cheer.
滚
Go!
他说的对
He has a point.
是啊
Yeah.
接下来怎么办
So what next?
假设洛布和法尔科内是唯一知道
Assume Loeb and Falcone are the only ones
证据藏匿点的人
who know where the stash is.
那我们需要一个亲近他们  并肯告诉我们的人
We need someone close to them, someone who'll talk.
哪有这样的人
That person doesn't exist.
有
Yeah, he does.
真不错
Oh, yes.
先生们
Gentlemen.
很高兴见到你们
So nice to see you.
有什么我能效劳的
What can I do for you?
你知道你的要求有多过分吧
You do realize what you're asking me to do?
如果法尔科内阁下确实
If Don Falcone is working with
与洛布局长勾结  暗中藏匿秘密文件
Commissioner Loeb to keep this trove of secrets hidden
而我帮你找到了
and I help you uncover them,
那我就是背叛了自己的老板
I'd be betraying my patron.
-没错  -如果被他发现
- That's right. - If he found out, he'd...
他会大发雷霆的
well, he'd be very angry.
这还是往轻了说
to say the least.
别唧唧歪歪了
Enough with the hemming and hawing.
你到底帮不帮我们
Are you gonna help us or not?
假如我帮了你们
Let say, for argument's sake, I could help you.
我能得到什么好处
What's in it for me?
那我就欠你一个人情
I'll owe you a favor.
不管我要什么都行吗
No questions asked?
吉姆
Jim.
是
Yes.
知道这是什么吗
Do you know what this is?
马德雷瓷罐
Madre Di Dios.
是由意大利乡间的修道士制作的
A hundred bottles made once a year
一年只做100个
by monks in the Italian countryside.
马罗尼阁下最喜欢了
It's Don Maroni's favorite.
你想说什么
What's your point?
这只是一条将来哪天可能用得上的信息
Oh, it's just a piece of information that might be useful one day.
我喜欢收集信息
I like information.
如果我帮你们找到洛布藏文件的地点
If I help you find where Loeb keeps his files,
给我10分钟单独接触文件的时间
you give me ten minutes alone with them.
让我把想要的拿走
I take what I want.
这不是个好主意
This is not a good idea.
5分钟
Five minutes.
而且关于警察的文件不能看
And you don't touch anything that has to do with cops.
5分钟查看文件  外加吉姆・戈登的人情
Five minutes with the files and a favor from Jim Gordon?
成交
Done!
上路吧
So who's up for a road trip?
我们得再给菲什点时间
We have to give Fish more time.
她会带我们出去的  她答应过的
She'll get us out of here; she promised.
你还没看出来吗  她抛弃我们了
Can't you see she abandoned us?
自己跑路  不管我们死活了
Got herself out and left us here to rot.
要我说  我们杀了这家伙
I say we kill this one,
让他们知道我们不是好惹的
let them know we're serious.
-菲什说了...  -菲什  菲什  菲什
- Fish said... - Fish, Fish, Fish.
菲什现在在哪
Where's Fish now?!
我很失望
I'm disappointed.
我说了  我会回来的
I told you I was coming back.
怎么  你们不相信我吗
What, you didn't believe me?
信任是家庭的根基  我们正是如此
Family is built on trust, and that's what we are.
是一家人
A family.
菲什  我劝过他们了
Fish, I tried, I did.
我知道
I know you did.
那你承诺的一切呢
So where's everything you promised?
我们什么时候能出去
When do we get out?
一件件地来
First thing's first.
我和楼上的人谈过了
I spoke to the man upstairs
说了我们的要求  更好的居住条件和餐饮
about our demands for better conditions, better food.
他要求我们也表示一下诚意
He asked for a show of good faith.
要把守卫还给他
We're gonna return his guard.
放他走
Let him go.
立刻
Now.
接下来
Next...
干什么
What?
他们要干什么
What are they doing?
对不起了  亲爱的
I'm sorry, honey.
你在单子上  医生的订单
You're on the list. Doctor's orders.
菲什  菲什
Fish... Fish!
我告诉过你们了吧
I told you, didn't I?
她在为他们卖命了
She's working for them now!
我提醒过你们不是每个人都能活下来
I warned you not everyone would live.
他们的牺牲代表了你们能活下来
Their sacrifice means your survival!
我的承诺依然不变
And my promise remains the same.
你确定吗  企鹅
You sure about this, Penguin?
你说这里就是洛布保存了20年
You're telling me this is where Loeb keeps 20 years
肮脏秘密的地方
of dirty secrets?
感觉不对啊
Doesn't feel right.
也许要的就是这样
Well, maybe that's the point.
别人才不会怀疑
No one would suspect it.
你以为会是什么样的地方  布洛克警探
What would you prefer, Detective Bullock?
门口挂个大招牌写着"超级秘密敲诈仓库"吗
A sign saying "Super secret blackmail hoard"?
记得吗  上次我们三个一起出来兜风的时候
You know, the last time the three of us took a ride,
你在后备箱里
you were in the trunk.
我还是喜欢那回
I liked that better.
我说了
I told you,
我偷听到了法尔科内跟洛布的通话
I overheard Falcone on the phone to Loeb.
他说农场很安全
He said the farm was safe.
好了  我在车里等  你们搞定了
Now, I'll wait here, and when you're done,
就给我闪几下手电筒什么的
flash the lights or something.
你要跟我们一起去
You're coming along.
但要是里面的人看见了我  报告给法尔科内...
But if whoever's inside sees me and reports back to Falcone...
那你就死定了
Then you'll be in some really deep doo.
不然你想怎样
What'd you think, huh?
我们替你把脏活儿都干了
We were gonna go do your dirty work,
然后你就悠悠然地走进来
and then you were just gonna waltz in
把好处全捞走
and pick through the leavings?
放尊重点
Have some respect.
你们迷路了吗
You fellas lost?
晚上好  先生
Good evening, sir.
是洛布局长派我们过来的
We were sent by Commissioner Loeb.
我们能进去谈谈吗
Might we have a word?
外面好冷
Out of the cold?
玛姬正在煮茶
Well, Marge is putting on some tea.
我喜欢你们的房子
I love your house.
-很温馨  -谢谢
- It's so cozy. - Thank you.
你们在这儿住多久了
How long have you two been here?
那可有20年了吧
Oh, well, about, uh, 20 years.
洛布先生买下这里后我们就一直这儿了
Ever since Mr. Loeb bought the place.
真难以置信
Hard to believe.
时光飞逝啊
Time, boy.
你们真该看看玛姬那时候的样子
You should've seen Margie back then.
从美人变成了老太婆
Hot to trot.
那之前你们是做什么的
What were you doing before that?
不值一提  玛姬是阿卡姆疯人院的护士
Oh, nothing much. Uh, Margie was a nurse over at Arkham.
而我在铁路公司工作
And I working on the railroad.
你们为什么事来
Why are you men here?
来视察
Inspection.
洛布局长对安全问题有点担忧
Commissioner Loeb has some concerns about security.
我们没听说这回事
We didn't hear nothing about it.
你们没收到信吗
You didn't get a letter?
没有
No.
那就怪了
That's odd.
你们应该收到了才对
Y-You should have gotten a letter.
你们带证件了吗
You got I.D.?
我觉得没有这个必要
Well, I don't know that that's necessary.
不  没关系
No, no. It's fine.
吉姆・戈登  哥谭市警局
Jim Gordon, GCPD.
这位是布洛克警探
This is Detective Bullock.
我们是局长的私人保镖
We're on the Commissioner's personal detail.
他看起来不像是警察
He don't look like a cop.
我是卧底
I'm undercover.
该死的浣熊
Damn raccoons.
吉姆  不如我们开始视察吧
Jim, what do you say we get on with our inspection?
不介意的话麻烦带路
Perhaps you wouldn't mind showing us around.
当然
Oh, absolutely.
玛姬  把我的钥匙拿来好吗
Marge, would you mind fetching my keys?
好
Sure.
听我说
Now, listen,
你们走之前
before you go,
一定要尝尝玛姬的蛋糕
you fellas have got to get a piece of Marge's cake.
她用酸奶油做的
She makes it with sour cream.
味道像暖和的周日清晨一样美好
Tastes like a warm Sunday morning.
好大的浣熊啊
That's one hell of a big raccoon.
我们从楼上开始看吧
Maybe we should start upstairs.
等她拿钥匙
Oh, just wait a lick for the keys.
玛姬  挺快啊
Margie-pie, that was quick.
夫人  把枪放下
Ma'am, put down the...
别动
Freeze!
谢了  吉姆
Thanks, Jim.
-你救了我...  -看着他们
- You saved my li... - Watch them.
算你走运  我这人心疼老太太
You're lucky I have a soft spot for old ladies.
楼下好安静
I-It's so quiet downstairs.
派对结束了吗
Is the party over?
我准备了首歌
I-I prepared a song.
还配了舞蹈什么的
It includes a dance and everything.
你是谁
Who the hell are you?
我是米利亚姆・洛布
I'm Miriam Loeb.
是我父亲叫你们来的吗
Did-did my father send you?
柯林格小姐
Ms. Kringle.
尼格玛先生
Oh, Mr. Nygma.
柯林格小姐  不知道
Ms. Kringle, I was wondering
你今晚晚餐是否有安排了
if you had dinner plans this evening.
其实...还真有
Actually, I... I do.
和汤姆约好了
With Tom.
你们认识吗
Have-have you met Tom?
你是喜欢谜语的那个
You're the guy that likes riddles.
什么东西有手  但无法鼓掌
Hey, what has hands but can't clap?
钟[指针]
A clock.
没错
Correct.
他挺厉害
He's good.
你挺厉害
You're good.
那么这位是不是就是...
Am I correct to assume that this is your...
你的新男友
uh, your new boyfriend?
是啊  是的吧
Yeah... Yes, I guess so.
当然
You betcha.
恭喜  先生
Congratulations, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们该走了
Well, we should probably get going.
好
Okay.
认识你很高兴
It's nice to meet you.
谜语哥  下次
Riddle man, next time...
下次我一定难倒你
I'm gonna stump you.
嗯
Yes.
下次吧
Next time.
米利亚姆
So, Miriam,
你一直待在这上面吗
you live up here all the time?
是啊
Always.
自从...
Uh, ever since...
但我不是孤单一人
I, uh... I'm not alone though.
父亲周日会来看我
Father comes to visit on Sundays.
我们会一起听收音机节目  一起玩西洋棋
And we listen to the radio and play checkers.
他总放水
He always lets me win.
我爸爸以前也是
My dad used to do the same thing.
是吗
Really?
父亲就这样  是吧
Fathers are funny like that, aren't they?
是啊  你父亲可真好
Yeah, your dad's a real hoot.
他还在这里放别的东西吗
Does he keep other stuff up here?
重要的文件  档案
Like important papers or files or
或者一屋子的盒子什么的
maybe rooms full of boxes?
没有
No.
他干吗要那么做啊
Why would he do that?
这是浪费时间
This is a waste of time.
米利亚姆
Miriam...
你母亲出了什么事
...what happened to your mother?
她
She...
死了
died.
我
I, um...
我现在有新的爱好了
I've started a new hobby.
你们想看看吗
Would you like to see?
好啊
Sure.
太好了
Oh, great.
你干什么
What are you doing?
洛布的妻子20年前死了
Loeb's wife died 20 years ago.
因摔下楼梯摔裂头骨
Skull fracture from a fall down the stairs.
米利亚姆那时应该十几岁
Miriam would've been a teenager.
你觉得是洛布杀了她  这孩子是目击证人
So you think Loeb killed her? She was the witness?
所以他才一直藏着她
That's why he keeps her cooped up here?
你说不止我一个人有个科波特
You said I wasn't the only one with a Cobblepot.
或许这是他的
Maybe this is his.
我开始做首饰了
I started making jewelry.
是什么做的
What's it made of?
骨头
Bones.
椋鸟
Starlings.
它们
They, uh...
它们停在我窗沿上
they land on my windowsill,
你可以捉到它们
and... you can catch them
但是要很安静  一动不动
if you're really silent and still.
我能耐得住性子  安静不动
And I can be really silent and still.
像老鼠一样不出声
Silent as a mouse.
然后呢
Then what do you do?
我
I...
我挤碎它们的脑袋
crush the back of their heads.
我用大拇指狠狠按下去
I just press down with my thumb.
能发出...
It makes, like, a...
"嘭"的一声
a popping noise.
"嘭"
Pop.
米利亚姆
Miriam...
能跟我们说说你母亲的死吗
...can you tell us about your mother's death?
我是个好人
I'm a good person.
但有时候好人会犯错
Sometimes good people make mistakes.
父亲就这么说的
That's what Father said.
你对你母亲犯错了吗
Did you make a mistake with your mother?
就像鸟那样
Was it like what happens with the birds?
不是
No.
不是像鸟那样
Not like with the birds.
真傻
Silly.
我对她还得用烛台
I had to use a candlestick on her.
她还是唱个不停
She wouldn't stop singing either.
她知道那晚到我了
She knew that it was my night.
我应该在晚餐上表演的
I was supposed to perform at dinner.
不是她
Not her.
所以你就打了她  让她住口
So you hit her and she stopped.
你父亲掩盖了起来
And your dad covered it up.
他知道那晚到我了
He knew that it was my night.
对不起  吉姆
I'm sorry, Jim.
他们朝我冲了过来  我尽力了...
They-they came at me. I tried...
你找到洛布藏的东西了吗
Did you find what Loeb's hiding?
是在这里吗
Is it here?
是的
Yes.
我们说好的
Well, a deal's a deal.
你得让我进去
You have to let me in there.
这是谁
Who's he?
他看上去像只鸟
He looks just like a bird.
我喜欢鸟
Oh, I love birds.
看来你还是没学会敲门呢
I see you still haven't learned the art of knocking,
戈登警探
Detective Gordon.
米利亚姆病了
Miriam is sick.
她不是有意伤害她母亲的
She didn't mean to hurt her mother.
她就是...
She just...
有些冲动
has these urges.
如果你想曝光她的作为  请便吧
If you want to expose what she did, go ahead.
你以为我控制不了一桩丑闻吗
You think I can't weather the scandal?
你当然能了
I'm sure you could.
但你把她藏了20多年不是为了这个
But that's not why you kept her locked away for 20 years.
说说看啊
Do enlighten me.
我认为你爱她
I think you love her.
我认为你尽了一切可能不让她被关进阿卡姆
I think you've done everything you can to keep her out of Arkham.
你今后还会继续这么做
And you'll keep doing it.
你为了达到目的  要拿我女儿相要挟吗
You're willing to hold my daughter hostage to achieve your ends?
你比我想的冷酷多了
You're much colder than I thought.
看来是的
So it seems.
我今天就辞职
I'll hand in my resignation today.
别把米利亚姆扯进来
Just keep Miriam out of it.
不  你不能辞职
No, you're not resigning.
你下台  我又得应付别人了
You step down, I'll have someone else to deal with.
而且他很可能跟你一样  也是法尔科内的走狗
And chances are he'll be Falcone's lapdog, same as you.
对你呢
With you...
我有筹码
I have leverage.
你想要什么
So what do you want?
弗拉斯受审
Flass is tried.
公平公正
Fairly.
把你手里关于布洛克和哥谭市警局
And I want all the evidence you have on Bullock
所有其他警察的不利证据都交给哈维・丹特
and every other cop in the GCPD sent to Harvey Dent.
让他决定起诉谁
He'll decide who to prosecute.
不行
No.
我那么做  就死定了
I do that, I'm a dead man.
我爱米利亚姆  但我也爱这条命
I love Miriam, but I love living, too.
可以把布洛克的案卷给你
You can have Bullock's file.
其他的不行
But not the rest.
好吧
Fine.
不要动米利亚姆
And Miriam stays where she is.
就这些了吗
Is that all?
还有件事
There's one more thing.
跟戈登警探一起站在这里几乎都成习惯了
It's become something of a habit to stand up here with Detective Gordon,
但警察工会主席大选在即
but with the coming election for president of the policemen's union,
我首推戈登警探
there's no man I'd rather support.
谢谢  洛布局长
Thank you, Commissioner Loeb.
哥谭市警局迎来了新的一天
It's a new day in the GCPD.
抱歉错过了你风光的一刻
Sorry I missed your big moment.
我想着下次我再去
I figured I'd catch the next one.
你的案卷
Your file.
这是洛布手里关于你的一切了
It's everything Loeb has on you.
我一直讨厌那张照片
Always hated that picture.
知道吗  你告诉自己
You know, you tell yourself...
"我就做这一件坏事
..."I'll just do this one bad thing,
我日后做很多好事  就补回来了"
but all the good things I'll do later will make up for it."
但那不行
But they don't.
坏事还是坏事
There's still that bad thing.
企鹅会回来叫你还人情的
Penguin's gonna come asking for that favor.
小心点
Be careful.
我知道我们说好了
I know we had a deal.
我放你们走  你们能逃脱
I let you go, and you escape the inevitable punishment
因为辜负洛布局长
that will descend on your heads
而必然将遭受的惩罚
when Commissioner Loeb hears of your failure.
可惜  我只弄到
Unfortunately, I was only able
一张去亚利桑那的车票
to acquire one ticket to Arizona.
谁能逃呢
So who's it gonna be?
玛姬和我在一起20年了
Margie and I have been together for 20 years.
我们不会分开的
We're not splitting up.
生活有时候很残酷的
Life can be cruel sometimes.
我们怎么决定谁走
How do we decide who goes?
你们自己决定吧
I leave that in your hands.
等等
Wait a minute!
玛姬  玛姬
Margie! Margie!
天呐  好了
Oh my goodness, here, here we go.
好了
Here we go.
Here we go!
火车什么时候开
What time is the train?
没什么火车
Oh, there's no train.
-我就是需要你帮忙  -什么
- I just needed your help. - What?
我只剩一颗子弹了
I was down to one shell.
我在考虑引入萨尔萨舞之夜
I've been thinking of introducing salsa night.
你觉得我们的客人会喜欢吗
Do you think our guests would like that?
不会
No.
坦诚  很好
Honest. Good.
但我喜欢萨尔萨舞
But... I like salsa.
就周二了
Tuesday it is.
那么  你的任务完成了
So... you've completed your task,
供给线又启动了
and the lines of supply are open once again.
真是厉害
I am duly impressed.
给绝望之人一丝希望
Hope is a carrot easily dangled
是再简单不过的事  医生
in front of the desperate, Doctor.
你有资格获得奖励了
And you have earned your carrot.
欢迎加入管理层
Welcome to upper management.
你会发现这里的风景要比地下室好
I think you'll find the view better than in the basement.
事实上
In fact...
明白我为什么能信任你了吧
You see why I can trust you.
我为什么不担心你会背叛我  逃离这里
Why I'm not worried about you betraying me and escaping.
是啊  明白了
Yes. I see.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com